Guide to the Edward H. Chamberlin papers, 1896-2017 and undated RL.11776
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Edward H. Chamberlin papers
1896-2017 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Chamberlin, Edward, 1899-1967
RL.11776
31.5 Linear Feet 26 boxes
Edward H. Chamberlin (1899-1967) was an economist and professor at Harvard University. This collection consists of his correspondence, research, writings, and items of a personal nature.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged into series: Correspondence, Conferences and Organizations, Writings, Research and Notes, Academia, and Personal.
Biographical / Historical
Edward Hastings Chamberlin (1899-1967) was an American economist born in LaConner, Washington. He died at age 68 on July 16, 1967 in Cambridge, Massachusetts. He earned his undergraduate degree in economics at the University of Iowa in 1920, completed an M.A. in economics at the University of Michigan (where he took classes with Fred M. Taylor) in 1922, and completed his Ph.D. in Economics at Harvard University in 1927 (studying with Allyn Young). Chamberlin joined the Economics Department at Harvard in 1932 and would remain there until his retirement in 1965. During World War 2 Chamberlin served in the European theater of operations with the Office of Strategic Services (OSS), and was tasked by the Supreme Allied Command with insuring success of Allied troops through detecting enemy espionage and sabotage. Chamberlin consulted for Eisenhower's Council of Economic Advisers and Committee of the Arts and Sciences and lectured at the US State Department's Foreign Service Institute. He also had notable engagement with the Catholic Economic Association and Catholic Commission on Intellectual and Cultural Affairs.
Chamberlin is arguably most well known for developing the theory of monopolistic competition simultaneously with Joan Robinson. He wrote extensively on theories of competition and market structure (particularly monopolistic competition), product differentiation, firms' pricing decisions, excess capacity, economies of scale, and labor unions. Chamberlin had notable scholarly engagements with Cambridge, UK economists Richard Kahn, Nicholas Kaldor, and Joan Robinson, among others; and University of Chicago economists Milton Friedman, Frank Knight, and George Stigler.
Access Restrictions
Access restricted. In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records. Contact Research Services for more information.
Provenance
The Edward H. Chamberlin papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2019.
Collection Overview
The Edward H. Chamberlin papers document his career as an economist and professor. The collection provides an overview of his professional activities, particularly his research and writings on topics such as monopolistic competition, market structure, pricing behavior, economies of scale, and collective bargaining, among others. The collection also documents his correspondence with prominent economists and individuals such as Marice Allais, Luigi Einaudi, Dwight Eisenhower, Howard S. Ellis, Milton Friedman, John Kenneth Galbraith, Gottfried Haberler, Frank Hahn, Roy Harrod, Friedrich A. Hayek, Richard Kahn, Nicholas Kaldor, Frank Knight, Emil Lederer, Wassily Leontief, Abba Lerner, Gertrud Lovasy, Fritz Machlup, Hans Neisser, J. F. Normano, Francois Perroux, Dennis H. Robertson, Joan Robinson, Paul Samuelson, Thomas Schelling, Robert Schuman, Joseph Schumpeter, Ben Seligman, George Stigler, Frank Taussig, Gerhard Tintner, Jaroslav Vanek, Jacob Viner, and many others.
Along with his scholarship and writings, the collection documents Chamberlin's roles in the American Economic Association, American Academy of Arts and Sciences, Council of Economic Advisers, and the Rockefeller Foundation project to aid refugee scholars fleeing Europe during the 1930s; his editorship of the Quarterly Journal of Economics; his speaking engagements; expert testimony in legal proceedings and before houses of the United States Congress; and his departmental roles, committee work, and teaching contributions at Harvard. The collection also contains personal artifacts documenting Chamberlin's service in the National Guard during World War 1, his service as a member of the Office of Strategic Services (OSS) during World War 2, as well as awards and honorary degrees.
Economists -- United States; Microeconomics; Economics; Equilibrium (Economics); Monopolies -- Economic aspects; Labor unions; Monopolistic competition; Economies of scale; Competition, Imperfect; Product differentiation; Industrial organization (Economic theory); Competition; Pricing; Wages -- Effect of inflation on; Oligopolies -- Economic aspects; Harvard University -- Faculty; Harvard University -- Alumni; Robinson, Joan, 1903-1983; Kaldor, Nicholas, 1908-1986; Kahn, Richard F. (Richard Ferdinand), 1905-; Allais, Maurice; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969; Einaudi, Luigi, 1874-1961; Friedman, Milton, 1912-2006; Galbraith, John Kenneth, 1908-2006; Haberler, Gottfried, 1900-1995; Hahn, Frank; Harrod, Roy, 1900-1978; Knight, Frank H. (Frank Hyneman), 1885-1972; Leontief, Wassily W.,; Lerner, Abba P. (Abba Ptachya), 1903-1982; Lovasy, Gertrud; Machlup, Fritz, 1902-1983; Neisser, Hans, 1895-1975; Robertson, Dennis Holme, Sir, 1890-1963; Normano, J. F. (João Frederico), 1887-1945; Samuelson, Paul A. (Paul Anthony), 1915-2009; Schelling, Thomas C., 1921-2016; Schuman, Robert, 1886-1963; Schumpeter, Joseph A., 1883-1950; Seligman, Ben B.; Stigler, George J. (George Joseph), 1911-1991; Taussig, F. W. (Frank William), 1859-1940; Tintner, Gerhard, 1907-1983; Vanek, Jaroslav; Viner, Jacob, 1892-1970; United States. Office of Strategic Services; Council of Economic Advisers (U.S.); Rockefeller Foundation; Lederer, Emil, 1882-1939; Ellis, Howard Sylvester, 1898-1992; Taylor, F. M. (Fred Manville), 1855-1932; Young, Allyn Abbott, 1876-1929; Hayek, Friedrich A. von (Friedrich August), 1899-; Hotelling, Harold, 1895-; Harvard University. Department of Economics; Perroux, François, 1903-1987
- Correspondence, 1920-1966 and undated; 1
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains Chamberlin's personal and professional communications with and about various individuals. Notable correspondents include Marice Allais, William Baumol, Kenneth Boulding, Luigi Einaudi, Dwight Eisenhower, Howard S. Ellis, Milton Friedman, Ragnar Frisch, John Kenneth Galbraith, Gottfried Haberler, Frank Hahn, Roy Harrod, Friedrich A. Hayek, Harold Hotelling, Richard Kahn, Nicholas Kaldor, Frank Knight, Emile Lederer, Wassily Leontief, Abba Lerner, Gertrud Lovasy, Fritz Machlup, Hans Neisser, J. F. Normano, Dennis H. Robertson, Joan Robinson, Paul Samuelson, Thomas Schelling, Robert Schuman, Joseph Schumpeter, Ben Seligman, George Stigler, Frank Taussig, Gerhard Tintner, Jaroslav Vanek, Jacob Viner, among others. Of note is Chamberlin's correspondence with Haberler, Harrod, Kahn, Kaldor, Knight, Robinson, and Stigler about theories of competition and firm behavior; and extensive correspondence with close friend Howard S. Ellis. Files are arranged alphabetically by name.
  A researcher, Thibault Guicherd, who had been in contact with Chamberlin's descendants prior to the papers arriving at Duke created an index of Chamberlin's correspondence. Please contact Research Services to access a copy of this index. Note that due to rearrangement of correspondence files during processing and creation of this series, the file list below and Guicherd's index may not fully overlap.
  - A, 1943-1962 (Box 1)
  - Abbott, Lawrence, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Raymond, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Ainsworth, Gardner, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Allais, Maurice, 1946-1948 (Box 1)
    Includes correspondence in English and French about monopolistic competition
  - Albrecht, V. Norman, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Alderson, Wroe, 1934-1964 (Box 1)
    Includes correspondence about monopolistic competition and cost pricing
  - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1949-1950 (Box 1)
    Includes copy of endorsement written for book by Fellner
  - Altman, James, 1937 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Karl, 1937 (Box 1)
  - Andrews, Philip W. S., 1960-1963 (Box 1)
    Includes correspondence about exchanging articles and other routine matters
  - Arthur, Henry B., 1949-1950 (Box 1)
  - Ashton, Herbert, 1937 (Box 1)
  - Aubert-Krier, Jane, 1954 (Box 1)
    Includes correspondence in French about the theory of competition
  - B, 1927-1964 (Box 1)
  - Bagiotti, Tullio, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Bain, Joe S., 1964 (Box 1)
    Includes discussion of Stigler and Chicago price theory
  - Ballande, L., 1938 (Box 1)
  - Ballard, Margaret, 1937-1939 (Box 1)
    Includes recommendations sent to Federal Trade Commission and Barnard
  - Baroody, William, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Bassot, Jacques, 1949-1950 (Box 1)
  - Baumol, William J., 1963-1964 (Box 1)
    Includes correspondence about exchanging papers
  - Beach, Ed, 1936 (Box 1)
    Includes correspondence about models of imperfect competition
  - Behling, B. N., 1936-1938 (Box 1)
    Includes correspondence about theories of imperfect competition
  - Bell, James Washington, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Benningnet, Pierre, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Bennion, E. G., 1939-1950 (Box 1)
  - Biddle, Duke Angier, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Bilkey, Warren J., 1943-1962 (Box 1)
  - Bishop, Bob, 1961-1963 (Box 1)
  - Black, Duncan, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Book Announcements and Lists, 1956-1960 (Box 1)
    Includes advertisements and catalogs from book publishers
  - Boulding, Kenneth, 1950-1962 (Box 1)
    Includes correspondence about Boulding's views on economies of scale
  - Bowen, Howard, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Bradley, Philip D., 1958-1964 (Box 1)
  - Braybrooke, David, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Brems, Hans, 1948-1951 (Box 1)
    Includes correspondence about publishing and Brems's work on price agreements
  - Briefs, Godfrey, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Broude, Henry W., 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Bruce, David K. E., 1951 (Box 1)
  - Buck, Paul H., 1949 (Box 1)
  - Bundy, McGeorge, 1954-1958 (Box 1)
  - Burbank, H. H., 1934-1936 (Box 1)
  - Burns, Arthur R., 1937-1939 (Box 1)
  - C, 1929-1963 (Box 1)
  - Calf, John T., undated (Box 1)
  - Campbell, W. Glenn, 1960-1963 (Box 1)
  - Carson, John, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Carver, Thomas Nixon, 1943-1961 (Box 1)
  - Cassels, John M., 1939-1941 (Box 1)
  - Chang, Perry P., undated (Box 1)
  - Cheever, Daniel S., 1958 (Box 1)
  - Chipman, John, 1950 (Box 1)
    Includes letter about Chipman and his research
  - Clark, Gardner, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Clark, John M., 1949-1960 (Box 1)
    Includes correspondence about a paper by Chamberlin on competition and other routine matters
  - Claydon, Arthur, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Clower, Robert W., 1955 (Box 1)
    Includes correspondence about a paper Clower submitted to the Quarterly Journal of Economics
  - Coase, Ronald H., 1934-1935 (Box 1)
    Includes correspondence about a paper by Coase on duopoly
  - Coe, V. F., 1937 (Box 1)
  - Cole, Arthur H., 1948-1958 (Box 1)
  - Conrad, Alfred H., 1959 (Box 1)
  - Copeland, Morris A., 1962 (Box 1)
  - Crum, W. Leonard, 1958-1960 (Box 1)
  - Curtis, Charles W., 1950 (Box 1)
  - D, 1936-1964 (Box 1)
  - Daly, Frederick, 1929 (Box 1)
  - Dayre, Jean, 1962-1963 (Box 1)
  - de Chageau, Mel, 1936 (Box 1)
  - De Jong, F. J., 1962 (Box 1)
  - Dean, Joel, 1937 (Box 1)
  - Demsetz, Harold, 1963 (Box 1)
    Includes correspondence about a paper by Demsetz on monopolistic competition
  - Dennison, Henry, 1937 (Box 1)
  - Desai, Romeschchandra D., 1947 (Box 1)
  - Dewey, Davis R., 1936 (Box 1)
  - Dewhurst, Frederic, 1934 (Box 1)
  - Dickinson, Z. Clark, 1956-1957 (Box 1)
  - Dishman, Robert, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Douglas, Paul F., 1950 (Box 1)
  - Duvaux, Jacques, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Dykstra, L. A., 1949 (Box 1)
  - E, 1949-1961 (Box 1)
  - Economics of Recovery Program, 1933-1934 (Box 1)
    Includes newspaper clippings and correspondence related to commentaries on the New Deal
  - Eckstein, Otto, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Edwards, Corwin D., 1936-1962 (Box 1)
  - Einaudi, Luigi, 1950 (Box 1)
    Includes correspondence about circulating papers
  - Einaudi, Luigi (office of), 1950-1954 (Box 1)
    Includes correspondence about exchanging papers. Einaudi's letters were written on his behalf by an assistant
  - Eisenhower, Dwight, 1956-1957 (Box 1)
    Includes invitation to Presidential inauguration and documents from Chamberlin's participation on the Committee of the Arts and Sciences for Eisenhower
  - Elgen, Riley, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Ellis, Howard S., 1924-1963; 4 folders (Box 1)
    Includes correspondence about routine business and personal updates about Ellis and Chamberlin families
  - Enke, Stephen, 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Epstein, Ralph, 1949-1958 (Box 1)
  - F, 1936-1963 (Box 1)
  - Fairchild, Fred R., 1937 (Box 1)
  - Farnsworth, Frank A., 1948-1950 (Box 1)
  - Fellner, William, 1957 and undated (Box 1)
  - Fisher, Irving, 1937 (Box 1)
    Includes request for Chamberlin's bibliography on monopolistic competition
  - Fitzpatrick, Paul J., 1949 (Box 1)
  - Fowler, Sam, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Fox, Bert, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Friedman, Milton, 1948-1950 (Box 1)
    Includes correspondence discussing the impact of taxes on prices in models of perfect competition and monopolistic competition
  - Friedrich, Carl J., 1958 (Box 1)
  - Frisch, Ragnar, 1936-1937 (Box 1)
  - G, 1936-1964 (Box 1)
  - Galbraith, John Kenneth, 1938-1964 (Box 1)
    Includes correspondence about Joan Robinson and Richard Kahn's views on imperfect competition
  - Gardner, Walter, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Garnsey, Morris, 1937-1938 (Box 1)
  - Geren, Paul, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Gilson, Etienne, 1926 (Box 1)
    Includes letter written by the French philosopher
  - Givens, Meredith B., 1936 (Box 1)
    Includes correspondence related to a report Chamberlin wrote for the State of New York Department of Labor
  - Goldwater, Barry, 1958 (Box 1)
    Includes a thank you card from Goldwater and correspondence about Chamberlin's travel to testify before the U.S. Senate Committee on Labor and Public Welfare
  - Gordon, Ezekiel, 1958-1959 (Box 1)
  - Gotsch, Carl H., 1963 (Box 1)
  - Graham, Charles R., 1949 (Box 1)
  - Grossman, Gregory, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Guillebaud, C. W., 1962 (Box 1)
  - H, 1938-1964 (Box 2)
  - Haberler, Gottfried, 1935-1964 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about Haberler's views on Chamberlin's work, discussion of the Beveridge Report, and other routine matters
  - Hahn, Frank H., 1949-1963 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about Hahn's views on economies of scale and the refereeing process for a paper Chamberlin submitted to the Review of Economic Studies
  - Haley, B. F., 1950 (Box 2)
  - Hall, Thomas S., 1949 (Box 2)
  - Halm, George N., 1957 (Box 2)
  - Hamilton, Earl J., 1949 (Box 2)
  - Haney, Lewis, H., 1941-1949 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about theories of competition
  - Hanson, Twyla, 1950 (Box 2)
  - Harris, Norman A., 1937 (Box 2)
  - Harris, Seymour, 1946-1962 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about monopolistic competition
  - Harriss, C. Lowell, 1937 (Box 2)
  - Harrod, Roy F., 1956-1963 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about duopoly and full cost pricing
  - Hayek, Friedrich A., 1958-1964 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about Chamberlin sending Hayek writings on labor unions and other routine matters
  - Heidlebaugh, George E., 1939 (Box 2)
  - Higgins, B. H., 1937-1938 (Box 2)
  - Hirota, Sus, 1941 (Box 2)
  - Hoffman, Werner, 1962 (Box 2)
  - Homan, Paul T., 1950 (Box 2)
  - Hoover, Edgar, 1936 (Box 2)
  - Hotelling, Harold, 1930 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about duopoly
  - Hovey, Paul, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Howell, Paul L., 1936-1948 (Box 2)
  - Hunt, Pearson, 1937-1938 (Box 2)
  - Hutchinson, Kenneth, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Hutt, W. H., 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - I, 1949 and undated (Box 2)
  - Irwin, H. S., 1934 (Box 2)
  - J, 1949-1964 (Box 2)
  - Jacoby, Neil H., 1949 (Box 2)
  - Johnson, D. Gale, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Johnson, E. A., 1937 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about potential publishers for book on monopolistic competition
  - Johnson, Harry G., 1963 (Box 2)
  - Johr, W. A., 1937-1947 (Box 2)
  - Jossa, Bruno, 1960 (Box 2)
  - K, 1927-1950 (Box 2)
  - Kahn, Richard, 1930 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about a portion of Kahn's dissertation on duopoly
  - Kaldor, Nicholas, 1937-1942 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about Kaldor and Chamberlin's disagreement over the theory of monopolistic and imperfect competition
  - Kaplan, A. D. H., 1961 (Box 2)
  - Kelly, Paul C., 1949 (Box 2)
  - Kennedy, John F. (office of), 1958 (Box 2)
    Includes a letter written on Kennedy's behalf
  - Keyes, Lucille, 1945-1960 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about Keyes's thesis. Keyes was married to prominent architect Arthur Keyes.
  - Knight, Frank H., 1937-1950 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about theories of competition and economic theory more broadly
  - Kumaraswamy, M. R., 1961 (Box 2)
  - L, 1936-1958 (Box 2)
  - Lashly, Jacob M., 1949 (Box 2)
  - Le Duc, Gaston, 1936-1937 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about a Rockefeller Fellowship for Le Duc
  - Lederer, Emil, 1937-1938 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about market structure and equilibrium prices
  - Letter to the Editor, Boston Herald, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Leontief, Wassily, 1939 and undated (Box 2)
    Includes discussion about Leontief and his relationship with Harvard and a greeting card signed Leontief and students from Argentina
  - Lerner, Abba F., 1936-1949 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about economies of scale and publishing a response to an article by Hahn and McLeod that is critical of Chamberlin
  - Lerner, Joseph, 1949-1950 (Box 2)
  - Lion, D., 1946 (Box 2)
  - Little, I. D., 1950 (Box 2)
  - Lovasy, Gertrud, 1938 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about securing a visa for Lovasy to escape Europe
  - M, 1937-1960 (Box 2)
  - Machlup, Fritz, 1937 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about a paper by Machlup on monopolistic competition and Machlup potentially joining the editorial board of the American Economic Review
  - Mackell, Emily, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Mann, F. K., 1950 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about Chamberlin's writing on labor unions
  - Marget, Arthur, 1937 (Box 2)
  - Maroni, Yves, 1950-1951 (Box 2)
  - Maxwell, J. A., 1939 (Box 2)
  - McCabe, Edward, 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - McCormick, Carol, undated (Box 2)
  - McCracken, H. L., 1938 (Box 2)
  - McIsaac, A. M., 1936 (Box 2)
  - Meier, Gerald M., 1958 (Box 2)
  - Merriman, Robert, 1934 (Box 2)
  - Metzler, Lloyd, 1936-1937 (Box 2)
    Includes routine correspondence
  - Meyers, Albert L., 1950 (Box 2)
  - Mills, J. C., 1950 (Box 2)
  - Morrison, L. A., 1933 (Box 2)
  - Morse, Herbert C., 1938-1939 (Box 2)
  - N, 1934-1961 (Box 2)
  - Negishi, Takashi, 1962 (Box 2)
  - Neisser, Hans, 1951 (Box 2)
  - New York Herald Tribune, 1940 (Box 2)
    Includes a letter to the editor
  - Newbury, Frank D., 1949 (Box 2)
  - Nicholls, William, 1939 (Box 2)
  - Niveau, Maurice, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Normano, J. F., 1933 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about Nazi Germany's request to extradite Normano
  - Norris, Ruby Turner, 1940-1950 (Box 2)
  - Norton, John, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Nourse, Edwin G., 1945 (Box 2)
  - Nutter, G. Warren, 1950-1959 (Box 2)
    Includes routine correspondence about Nutter
  - O, 1950-1958 (Box 2)
  - Ohlin, Bertil, 1950 (Box 2)
    Includes routine letter about Chamberlin receiving a paper by Ohlin
  - Olsen, Mancur Jr., 1961 (Box 2)
  - Oppenheimer, Irene, 1939 (Box 2)
  - P, 1936-1963 (Box 2)
  - Palander, Tord, 1936 (Box 2)
  - Parsons, Wilfrid, 1939 (Box 2)
  - Paton, W. A., 1948 (Box 2)
  - Percy, Charles H., 1960 (Box 2)
  - Perroux, Francois, 1945-1952 (Box 2)
  - Preston, H. H., 1939 (Box 2)
  - Q, 1962 (Box 2)
  - R, 1937-1964 (Box 2)
  - Randall, Clarence B., 1949 (Box 2)
  - Rao, J. R., 1963 (Box 2)
  - Recent Clippings, 1960-1964 (Box 2)
    Includes periodical clippings and book catalogs
  - Rees, Albert, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Reprints (sent to), 1953-1957 and undated (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence related to sending article reprints to people and lists of recipients of reprints
  - Reynard, Charles O., 1938 (Box 2)
  - Robertson, Dennis H., 1953-1960 (Box 2)
    Includes routine correspondence and copy of an introduction for Robertson given by Chamberlin
  - Robinson, Dwight, 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - Robinson, Joan, 1951-1964 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about Robinson's and Chamberlin's disagreement about imperfect and monopolistic competition
  - Robinson, Romney, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Rockefeller, David, 1938 and undated (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about Rockefeller's thesis, holiday cards, and a wedding invitation
  - Rolph, Earl, 1938-1940 (Box 2)
  - Ross, Arthur M., 1950 (Box 2)
  - Rotwein, Eugene, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Rueff, Jacques, 1962-1964 (Box 2)
  - S, 1934-1964 (Box 2)
  - Saltonstall, Leverett, 1958-1961 (Box 2)
    Includes routine correspondence with the US Senator
  - Samuelson, Paul A., 1950 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about welfare economics, pricing by firms, and other routine matters
  - Sarkar, Benoy, 1946 (Box 2)
  - Sarton, Mary, 1943-1946 (Box 2)
  - Saville, Lloyd, 1950 (Box 2)
  - Sawyer, Charles, 1950 (Box 2)
  - Schelling, Thomas C., 1964 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about books in the Harvard University Press economics series
  - Schneider, Erich, 1937-1939 (Box 2)
  - Schultz, T. W., 1936 (Box 2)
  - Schuman, Robert, 1954 (Box 2)
    Includes telegram thanking Chamberlin for his role in hosting the French president's visit to Harvard
  - Schumpeter, Joseph, 1935-1949 and undated (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about Schumpeter's departure from the Department of Economics at Harvard and other personal correspondence
  - Schwartzman, David, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Seligman, Ben, 1948-1963 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about exchanging papers and some comments on monopolistic competition
  - Sellier, Francois, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Sharfman, Leo, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Sheldon, Charles S., 1945 (Box 2)
  - Shove, Margaret, undated (Box 2)
  - Schulman, Marshall D., 1955 (Box 2)
  - Siegel, Albert, 1937 (Box 2)
  - Silcock, T. H., 1952-1963 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about labor markets and labor unions, monopolistic competition, and other routine matters
  - Simpson, T. W., 1950 (Box 2)
  - Smith, Edward K., 1949 (Box 2)
  - Solo, Robert, 1939-1962 and undated (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about professional and personal updates from Solo and other routine matters
  - Somers, Harold, 1948-1949 (Box 2)
  - Soucey, Ronald, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Spiegel, Raya, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Spuehler, Donald, 1951-1956 and undated (Box 2)
  - Stigler, George J., 1949-1964 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about the American Economic Association's volume on price theory, organizing conference sessions on monopolistic competition, and other routine matters
  - Stocking, George W., 1950 (Box 2)
  - Stone, Larry, 1953 (Box 2)
  - Stories and Quotes - Econ, undated (Box 2)
    Includes various short quotes and stories by economists
  - Stovel, J. A., 1947 (Box 2)
  - Strachey, John, 1958 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence with a British Member of Parliament about Chamberlin and Robinson's views on imperfect competition
  - Swerling, Boris C., 1949-1950 (Box 2)
  - T, 1949-1962 (Box 2)
  - Taussig, Frank W., 1935-1938 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about the Quarterly Journal of Economics and other routine matters
  - Taylor, Fred M., 1920-1924 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence about Chamberlin and Howard Ellis preparing to take classes with Taylor at the University of Michigan
  - Taylor, Horace, 1937 (Box 2)
  - Tinbergen, Jan, 1958-1960 (Box 2)